Hello, English learners. Welcome
back to English Pod. My name is Marco.
And I'm Erica.
And today we're bringing
you another great lesson
for all of you who are
interested in shopping.
Especially those of you who are
interested in shopping for a car.
A car, exactly.
So we're going to give
you some great language
about describing a car
or characteristics of a car.
Yep.
And also some really
interesting language for shopping.
Yes, especially buying something
really big and expensive.
Yeah, like a car.
Yeah, so before we listen to our dialogue,
let's take a look at vocabulary preview.
Vocabulary preview.
On vocabulary preview today,
we're bringing you two words.
The first one is vehicle.
Vehicle.
So again, a vehicle is a machine, right?
Right, a machine that carries
people from one place to another.
So it's important to say
that a vehicle could be an
airplane, a car, a car, a
boat, even a bicycle, right?
Yep.
That's a vehicle.
Our second word is sedan.
sedan.
So a sedan is a type of car.
Exactly.
It's a type of car with four doors
that can fit five people inside.
So to make it more clear,
most taxis are sedans.
Exactly.
Right.
Yeah.
They have four doors,
five people can fit
in there, including the
driver, except taxis in Mexico.
They're not sedan.
They're little beetles.
Oh.
They're folks that I can
beetles, so those are not sedans.
But yeah, most countries
have sedans, it's taxis.
To give you some examples, like the Toyota
Corolla or a Toyota Camry is a sedan.
Yeah, yeah.
Maybe like a Volkswagen Jetta.
Is that it?
A Jetta?
Yeah, Jetta is a sedan.
Yeah.
Now we can listen to our dialogue.
And it's going to be at
enormous speed the first
time, but you don't
have to worry about it.
We'll come back and teach you some of
the important words from the dialogue.
Hi, there.
Can I help you folks?
I'm just browsing,
seeing what's on the lot.
My daughter wants a car for her birthday.
You know how it is.
Dad, I'm 16 already, and I'm like the
only one at school who doesn't have a car.
She's right, you know.
Kids these days all have cars.
Let me show you something we just
got in a 1996 sedan, excellent gas mileage.
It has dual airbags and anti-like brakes,
a perfect vehicle for a young driver.
Dad, I love it.
It's awesome.
Can we get this one, please?
I see.
What can you tell me about this one?
Oh, that's just an old World War II
tank that we use for TV commercials.
Now about this today.
Whoa, whoa, wait a minute.
Tell me more about this tank.
Well, sir, if you are looking for
quality and safety, then look no further.
Three inches of reinforced
steel, protect your
daughter from
short-range missile attacks.
Does the sedan protect
her from missile attacks?
It does not.
Well, I don't know.
Let me sleep on it.
Did I mention the tank?
Is it tank?
I'll take it.
Dad.
I think she's really lucky.
Really?
Getting a tank to go to
school, how awesome is that?
I would be so embarrassed if I
had to drive to school in a tank.
It's like the coolest car.
Oh, you're such a boy.
All right, a surprising ending
to a relatively easy shopping day.
Yeah.
Let's take a look at some language that we
saw in our dialogue on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
We have four words for you today.
The first one is gas mileage.
Gas mileage.
So, gas mileage is how many miles you can
travel on a gallon or a liter of gasoline.
Well, you know what's interesting?
In some English-speaking
countries like
Australia, New Zealand,
Canada, we use kilometers
to measure distance, but
we still talk about gas mileage.
Hmm.
Yep.
Well, guess you can't say gas kilo mileage.
No.
It's something good.
But yeah, it's, yeah, basically
how many kilometers or how many
miles you can travel on a tank
or on a liter or gallon of gas.
Exactly.
Okay.
The next word is airbags.
Airbags.
These are like big
bags of air that fill up
and come out of the
car when there is a crash.
Right.
So that way you don't hit your head
against steering wheel or stuff like that.
So they protect you.
Right.
I've heard that Volvo has like
18 airbags now in their cars.
They are very safe cars, you know?
Like a big balloon.
Uh huh.
Okay.
Our third word today is brakes.
Brakes.
So what are brakes?
Brakes are little, what are brakes?
Brakes are what make your car stop.
Okay.
So they're the little machines
maybe that stop your car?
Yeah.
They're on the wheels.
They make your car stop.
Uh-huh.
Our last word today
on language, take away
reinforced reinforced
reinforced reinforced.
So we have some examples of how we use
reinforced because it's a little bit weird.
Yeah.
These will help you understand
the meaning example one.
So I reinforced all the walls.
There's no way they're going to fall down.
Example two.
This plastic is reinforced with a
glass so it's both light and strong.
So basically anything that's
reinforced is made stronger.
Perfect.
Reinforced.
Reenforced table.
Uh-huh.
Okay.
Great.
Again, you can practice
all these words that we
just talked about and
we'll come back shortly.
Hi there.
Can I help you folks?
I'm just browsing,
seeing what's on the lot.
My daughter wants a car for her birthday.
You know how it is.
Dad, I'm 16 already and I'm like the
only one at school who doesn't have a car.
She is right, you know.
Kids these days all have cars.
Let me show you something we just got in.
A 1996 Sudan, excellent gas mileage.
It has dual airbags and anti-lock brakes,
a perfect vehicle for a young driver.
Dad, I love it.
It's awesome.
Can we get this one, please?
I see.
What can you tell me about this one?
Oh, that's just an old World War II
tank that we use for TV commercials.
Now about this sedan,
whoa, whoa, wait a minute.
Tell me more about this tank.
Well, sir, if you are looking for
quality and safety, then look no further.
Three inches of reinforced
steel, protect your
daughter from
short-range missile attacks.
Does the Sudan protect
her from missile attacks?
It does not.
Well, I don't know.
Let me sleep on it.
Did I mention the tank is a tank?
I'll take it.
Dad.
So we have a couple of interesting
phrases to talk about shopping.
Right.
Let's look at these in Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
The first one today is I'm just browsing.
I'm just browsing.
This is a really useful
phrase because usually
salespeople will come
up to you and ask
you, can I help you or
you're sitting in something?
Yeah.
And you're just looking, so... Yeah,
you maybe you don't really want to buy it.
Right.
So you're just browsing.
So then they'll just leave you alone.
Yeah, they won't buy that you as much.
Yeah, that's a good, good phrase.
Another good phrase.
Sleep on it.
So we have some examples
of how we use sleep on it.
One.
I don't know if we should buy that house.
It's perfect for us, but it's so expensive.
Let's sleep on it.
Example two.
Why don't you sleep on
it and tell me tomorrow?
I don't want to see anybody else like that.
Example three.
This is a bit more than what I can afford.
Let me sleep on it.
To sleep on it means to...
Like to think about it overnight.
To think about it.
Yeah.
So maybe you want to buy this really
expensive car, but you need to think about it.
Right.
So you'll sleep on it.
You go home.
Sleep on it.
Think about it twice
and then make a decision.
Exactly.
Okay.
Great words and great dialogue.
Yeah.
I love this dialogue.
It's kind of funny.
So we could listen to
it again and then we'll
come back and talk
a little bit about it.
I'm just browsing seeing what's on the lot.
My daughter wants a car for
her birthday, you know how it is.
Dad, I'm 16 already and I'm like feeling
one at school who doesn't have a car.
She's right, you know.
Kids these days all have cars.
Let me show you something we just
got in a 1996 sedan, excellent gas mileage.
It has dual airbags and anti-elect brakes,
a perfect vehicle for a young driver.
Dad, I love it.
It's awesome.
Can we get this one, please?
I see.
What can you tell me about this one?
Oh, that's just an old World War II
tank that we use for TV commercials.
Now about this today.
Whoa.
Wait a minute.
Tell me more about this tank.
Well, sir, if you are looking for
quality and safety, then look no further.
Three inches of reinforced
steel protect your
daughter from short
range missile attacks.
Does the sedan protect
her from missile attacks?
It does not.
Well, I don't know.
Let me sleep on it.
Did I mention the tank?
Is it tank?
I'll take it.
Dad.
So Marco, have you ever driven a tank?
Well, I mean, I know you're in the Army.
Yeah.
Yeah, actually I did.
I did drive a tank before.
Really?
Really old one, kind of like
a World War II type tank.
But yeah, they're really
fun and interesting.
It's not like driving a normal car.
You have pedals and games.
But there's no steering wheel?
No, no, no.
You have levers.
Yeah.
And what many people don't know is that
actually tanks are manual transmissions.
You have to change gears.
Oh, really?
And it's really hard to
change gears on those things.
And what's the gas mileage like in a tank?
I don't know.
Maybe like five miles per gallon.
OK.
They run on diesel, which has
a different type of fuel, right?
Yep.
OK, well, very cool.
I never knew that my podcast
partner had driven a tank.
That's pretty awesome.
Yeah, well, it was fun, definitely.
And I hope I get to do it again someday.
All right.
Well, guys, have you ever driven a tank?
Or a submarine or any
type of armored vehicle?
Yeah, tell us about it at our website.
EnglishPod.com.
Right.
We'll be there to
answer all your questions.
I'll also be there to maybe
post some more crazy stories.
Or some pictures of the tank.
Yeah, maybe.
Yeah.
All right, guys, we'll see you there.
Until then, it's goodbye.
[MUSIC PLAYING]